<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="Menuinfo">Eartquake\'s Information</string>
    <string name="Menuprev">Prevention\'s Information</string>
    <string name="Menuplan">My Plan</string>
    <string name="Menudesafios">Games</string>

    <string name="app_name">SismicApp</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="radio_button">Radio Button</string>
    <string name="str_next">Next</string>
    <string name="title_activity_result">Results!!!</string>
    <string name="pepito">Test of lenguaje</string>
    <string name="titulo_richter">Richter\'s Scale</string>
    <string name="titulo_infosismos">Earthquake\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_mercali">Mercalli\'s Scale</string>
    <string name="info_Richter">Unlike the scale of Mercalli, Richter’s scale measure the force of the earthquakes according to their magnitude, that is to say, the quantity of released energy during the earthquake. This gauge is made using the data that is delivered by a seismograph, a device in charge of register all seismic waves. Therefore it doesn’t have a clear limit of degrees."\n""\n"
        Until now, the biggest magnitud registered in the world Correspond to a 9,5 degrees, that earthquake happened In Valdivia, Chile, in the year 1960. This is a scale that uses Scientific data and not people’s perceptions. We could get some some expected consequences according to a certain registered magnitude."\n""\n"
        The following table shows the scale in a generalized manner, by one side you can observe the measurement in degrees and in the other side the observed effects on earth."\n""\n"</string>
    <string name="info_infosismos_info">An Earthquake, a tremor or a seism is a sudden perturbation in the inside of the Earth that generates vibrations on the ground; the principal cause and the responsible for the mayority of earthquakes is the fracture and rupture of the rocks on the most external layers of the Earth, generating to a series of sismic waves that propagates across the internal parts of the Earth and when they get to the surface, they are perceive as earthquakes."\n""\n"
        In the World exists zones with a great tendency to experience more tremors. This regions are in places were the concentration of forces generated by the boundaries of tectonic plates causes movements of readjustment are more frequent, both within the interior of the crust as on the surface of the Earth. "\n""\n"
        The place were the rupture start on the inside  of the Earth it’s called the focus or hypocenter and the place on the terrestrial surface that receives the sismic waves it’s called epicentre. The seismic event is similar to The action of flipping an object to a pond, in this case the energy released by the shockwave generated between the object and the water surface it manifest trough a series of waves that move away in a concentric manner from the center were the object fall. "\n""\n"</string>
    <string name="info_mercalli">In a scale of 12 points, identifiying each point with Roman numbers, this scale was developed to assess the intensity of the earthquakes through the effects and damage to various structures. This is a subjective scale, because evaluates the human’s perception of the earthquake. It proves useful when recollecting information on regions where it doesn’t exists detection devices or other tools of measurement. It is based, as previously mentioned above, as how the people felt while experiencing an earthquake, or in the damage sustained on others  structures."\n""\n"
        When one uses this scale, the people refers to intensity degrees. "\n""\n"
        Next, is following a table with all 12 points of this scales and their respective evaluations.Also, it exist evidence of another gauge, the peak ground acceleration, a concept that which will comment later."\n""\n"</string>
    <string name="titulo_bienvenidasismos">Welcome to Earthquake\'s information</string>

    <string name="titulo_bienvenidaprev">Welcome to Prevention\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_quehacersismo">What to do in an earthquake?</string>
    <string name ="info_quehacersismo">First you must keep calm and protect in a safe zone in the place where you are. Once the quake ends you must go to the escape routes and remember not to use elevators. Also be prepared and take precautions in your home, planning the following: "\n" "\n"
-Agree a safe place to shelter and a meeting place if your family group dispersion during the earthquake. "\n"
-Check that your housing facilities both electric and gas, are in good condition. "\n"
-Prepare an emergency kit with basic items. "\n"
-Identify risk objects such as pictures, objects can move or break windows, staying away from them during the quake. "\n" "\n"
</string>
    <string name="titulo_lugarseguro">Safe place</string>
    <string name="info_lugarseguro">If during an earthquake are in an inner safety zones correspond to the toughest parts of a good construction, which are usually the corners, corners, pillars and the area under the doorframe. "\n" "\n"
If you are outside, find a safe place walking away tambourines, buildings, ledges, pipes chimneys, trees, poles, power lines or other potential danger. "\n" "\n"
</string>
    <string name="titulo_lugardeencuentro">Agree on a meeting place</string>
    <string name="info_lugardeencuentro">It is very important that you define in advance a meeting with your household in case of an earthquake, communications may be cut. This place should be accessible to all and safe. "\n" "\n"</string>
    <string name="titul_kit">Emergency Kit</string>
    <string name="info_kit">It consists of the basic elements that should be in an earthquake: "\n" "\n"
-	Flashlight with batteries "\n"
-	Battery-powered radio. "\n"
-	Extra batteries. "\n"
-	Kit, which has at least disinfectant, cotton, gauze, tape, band aids, aspirin. "\n"
-	Energy Food and / or canned for about 5 days. "\n"
-	Bottled water. "\n"
-	Coats. "\n"
-	Plastic bags to store your garbage. "\n"
-	Toilet paper and / or tissues. "\n" "\n"

</string>
</resources>
