<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="Menuinfo">Eartquake\'s Information</string>
    <string name="Menuprev">Prevention\'s Information</string>
    <string name="Menuplan">My Plan</string>
    <string name="Menudesafios">Games</string>

    <string name="app_name">SismicApp</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="str_next">Next</string>
    <string name="title_activity_result">Results!!!</string>
    <string name="titulo_richter">Richter\'s Scale</string>
    <string name="titulo_infosismos">Earthquake\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_mercali">Mercalli\'s Scale</string>
    <string name="titulo_bienvenidasismos">Welcome to Earthquake\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_bienvenidaprev">Welcome to Prevention\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_quehacersismo">What to do in an earthquake?</string>
    <string name="titulo_lugarseguro">Safe place</string>

    <string name="long_infosismos_info">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations in the ground; main and responsible for most of the earthquakes cause is rupture and fracturing of rocks in the outermost layers of the earth, giving rise a series of seismic waves propagating inside the earth and reaching the surface are perceived as an earthquake. The site where the rupture starts is called the focus (hypocenter) and place on the surface that is directly above the Earth\'s surface is called the epicenter. "\n" "\n"
There are areas that are more prone to earthquakes. These are regions where the concentration of forces generated by the boundaries of tectonic plates makes adjustment movements are more frequent, both within the earth\'s crust and on the surface of the Earth.
</string>
    <string name="short_infosismos_info">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations in the...</string>
    <string name="long_infosismos_summary">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations in the ground. The site where the rupture starts is called the focus (hypocenter) and place on the surface that is directly above the Earth\'s surface is called the epicenter.</string>
    <string name="short_infosismos_summary">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations...</string>
    <string name="long_infosismos_dato">The seismic phenomenon is similar to the fact throw an object into a pool of water. In that case the energy released by the collision of the object with the surface of water occurs through a series of waves that deviate concentrically to where the object fell.</string>
    <string name="short_infosismos_dato">The seismic phenomenon is similar to the fact throw an object into a pool of...</string>

    <string name="long_escrit_info">The Richter scale was created in 1935 by Charles Richter, seismologist born in 1900. Richter wanted to develop a quantitative way to compare earthquakes, which did not depend on the location of the observer. Unlike the Mercalli scale, Richter measures the strength of earthquakes according to their magnitude, that is, the amount of energy released during an earthquake. This measurement is performed using the data delivered by seismographs, equipment makers recorded seismic waves. Therefore, it has no limit degrees. "\n" "\n"
This is a scale that uses scientific data and not perceptions of people. We can identify some possible expected effects, according to the magnitude recorded. At the beginning of the century, most seismologists considered obsolete traditional magnitude scales, these being replaced by a more physically meaningful measurement called the seismic moment, which is more appropriate to relate the physical parameters such as the size of the seismic rupture and the energy released by an earthquake.
</string>
    <string name="short_escrit_info">The Richter scale was created in 1935 by Charles Richter, seismologist born in 1900. Richter...</string>
    <string name="long_escrit_summary">The Richter scale measures the strength of earthquakes according to their magnitude, that is, the amount of energy released during an earthquake. This measurement is performed using the data delivered by seismographs, equipment makers recorded seismic waves.</string>
    <string name="short_escrit_summary">The Richter scale measures the strength of earthquakes according to their magnitude, that is...</string>
    <string name="long_escrit_dato">So far, the largest magnitude recorded in the world corresponds to 9.5 degrees, to the earthquake in Valdivia, Chile, in 1960. If there was an earthquake of magnitude 10 degrees, this would be equivalent to the shock of a stony meteorite 2 km diameter impact at 25 km/s (90,000 km/h).</string>
    <string name="short_escrit_dato">So far, the largest magnitude recorded in the world corresponds to 9.5 degrees, to the earthquake...</string>

<string name="long_escmerc_info">It is a scale of 12 points, each identified by Roman numerals, developed to assess the intensity of earthquakes through the effects and damage to various structures. "\n" "\n"
It is a subjective scale, because human perception evaluates the quake. Serves to collect information in areas where no detection devices, or measuring instruments. It is based, as mentioned above, in what felt people who lived through the earthquake, or damage. When this scale is used, speaking of degrees of intensity. "\n" "\n"
It has undergone several changes through history, originally possessed only 10 points, then step 12 being Grade 1 very weak, since in favorable conditions are not perceived and being grade 12 the maximum where there is total destruction with few survivors . Levels and perspectives are distorted. Currently, the scale known as the Modified Mercalli scale (MM).
</string>
    <string name="short_escmerc_info">It is a scale of 12 points, each identified by Roman numerals, developed to assess the intensity of...</string>
    <string name="long_escmerc_summary">Mercalli scale assesses the intensity of earthquakes through the effects and damage to various structures (houses, buildings, etc.), because this in one country may be greater Mercalli scale in another country even though they have undergone a seismic tremor of equal magnitude (Richter scale for example).</string>
    <string name="short_escmerc_summary">Mercalli scale assesses the intensity of earthquakes through the effects and damage to various...</string>
    <string name="long_escmerc_dato">Did you know that despite its creation in 1906 by Giuseppe Mercalli, the last change that took this scale was made by the same creator Charles Richter scale of seismic intensity.</string>
    <string name="short_escmerc_dato">Did you know that despite its creation in 1906 by Giuseppe Mercalli, the last change that took this...</string>
</resources>
