<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="Menuinfo">Eartquake\'s Information</string>
    <string name="Menuprev">Prevention\'s Information</string>
    <string name="Menuplan">My Plan</string>
    <string name="Menudesafios">Games</string>

    <string name="app_name">SismicApp</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="str_next">Next</string>
    <string name="title_activity_result">Results!!!</string>
    <string name="titulo_richter">Richter\'s Scale</string>
    <string name="titulo_infosismos">Earthquake\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_mercali">Mercalli\'s Scale</string>
    <string name="titulo_bienvenidasismos">Welcome to Earthquake\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_bienvenidaprev">Welcome to Prevention\'s information</string>
    <string name="titulo_quehacersismo">What to do in an earthquake?</string>
    <string name="titulo_lugarseguro">Safe places</string>
    <string name="titulo_kit">Emergency Kit</string>

    <string name="long_infosismos_info">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations in the ground; main and responsible for most of the earthquakes cause is rupture and fracturing of rocks in the outermost layers of the earth, giving rise a series of seismic waves propagating inside the earth and reaching the surface are perceived as an earthquake. The site where the rupture starts is called the focus (hypocenter) and place on the surface that is directly above the Earth\'s surface is called the epicenter. "\n" "\n"
There are areas that are more prone to earthquakes. These are regions where the concentration of forces generated by the boundaries of tectonic plates makes adjustment movements are more frequent, both within the earth\'s crust and on the surface of the Earth.
</string>
    <string name="short_infosismos_info">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations in the...</string>
    <string name="long_infosismos_summary">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations in the ground. The site where the rupture starts is called the focus (hypocenter) and place on the surface that is directly above the Earth\'s surface is called the epicenter.</string>
    <string name="short_infosismos_summary">Earthquakes are sudden disturbances within the earth that give rise to vibrations...</string>
    <string name="long_infosismos_dato">The seismic phenomenon is similar to the fact throw an object into a pool of water. In that case the energy released by the collision of the object with the surface of water occurs through a series of waves that deviate concentrically to where the object fell.</string>
    <string name="short_infosismos_dato">The seismic phenomenon is similar to the fact throw an object into a pool of...</string>

    <string name="long_escrit_info">The Richter scale was created in 1935 by Charles Richter, seismologist born in 1900. Richter wanted to develop a quantitative way to compare earthquakes, which did not depend on the location of the observer. Unlike the Mercalli scale, Richter measures the strength of earthquakes according to their magnitude, that is, the amount of energy released during an earthquake. This measurement is performed using the data delivered by seismographs, equipment makers recorded seismic waves. Therefore, it has no limit degrees. "\n" "\n"
This is a scale that uses scientific data and not perceptions of people. We can identify some possible expected effects, according to the magnitude recorded. At the beginning of the century, most seismologists considered obsolete traditional magnitude scales, these being replaced by a more physically meaningful measurement called the seismic moment, which is more appropriate to relate the physical parameters such as the size of the seismic rupture and the energy released by an earthquake.
</string>
    <string name="short_escrit_info">The Richter scale was created in 1935 by Charles Richter, seismologist born in 1900. Richter...</string>
    <string name="long_escrit_summary">The Richter scale measures the strength of earthquakes according to their magnitude, that is, the amount of energy released during an earthquake. This measurement is performed using the data delivered by seismographs, equipment makers recorded seismic waves.</string>
    <string name="short_escrit_summary">The Richter scale measures the strength of earthquakes according to their magnitude, that is...</string>
    <string name="long_escrit_dato">So far, the largest magnitude recorded in the world corresponds to 9.5 degrees, to the earthquake in Valdivia, Chile, in 1960. If there was an earthquake of magnitude 10 degrees, this would be equivalent to the shock of a stony meteorite 2 km diameter impact at 25 km/s (90,000 km/h).</string>
    <string name="short_escrit_dato">So far, the largest magnitude recorded in the world corresponds to 9.5 degrees, to the earthquake...</string>

    <string name="long_escmerc_info">It is a scale of 12 points, each identified by Roman numerals, developed to assess the intensity of earthquakes through the effects and damage to various structures. "\n" "\n"
It is a subjective scale, because human perception evaluates the quake. Serves to collect information in areas where no detection devices, or measuring instruments. It is based, as mentioned above, in what felt people who lived through the earthquake, or damage. When this scale is used, speaking of degrees of intensity. "\n" "\n"
It has undergone several changes through history, originally possessed only 10 points, then step 12 being Grade 1 very weak, since in favorable conditions are not perceived and being grade 12 the maximum where there is total destruction with few survivors . Levels and perspectives are distorted. Currently, the scale known as the Modified Mercalli scale (MM).
</string>
    <string name="short_escmerc_info">It is a scale of 12 points, each identified by Roman numerals, developed to assess the intensity of...</string>
    <string name="long_escmerc_summary">Mercalli scale assesses the intensity of earthquakes through the effects and damage to various structures (houses, buildings, etc.), because this in one country may be greater Mercalli scale in another country even though they have undergone a seismic tremor of equal magnitude (Richter scale for example).</string>
    <string name="short_escmerc_summary">Mercalli scale assesses the intensity of earthquakes through the effects and damage to various...</string>
    <string name="long_escmerc_dato">Did you know that despite its creation in 1906 by Giuseppe Mercalli, the last change that took this scale was made by the same creator Charles Richter scale of seismic intensity.</string>
    <string name="short_escmerc_dato">Did you know that despite its creation in 1906 by Giuseppe Mercalli, the last change that took this...</string>
    //~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ Prevencion ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
        <string name="long_comoactuar_info">Upon the occurrence of an earthquake usually people do not know what to do, fear makes the mind is clouded and you tend to make mistakes, have water available is a good idea, but you have for a period of at least a week, not a bottle, placed behind a door is also not beneficial as it can be hit by the door as it swings violently or be crushed by the people trying to go if it\'s in a public place. "\n" "\n"
Electricity, water, gas and telephone systems is highly likely not to work after an earthquake. The police and fire department will be in more complicated situations. "\n" "\n"
If you are driving, the car traffic moves and stops. Avoid stopping near bridges or overpasses. Try to stay away from street lights, signs and power lines. To resume driving, watch for road hazards (fallen poles or uneven terrain) If you\'re in the mountains, watch the landslide. Similarly, if you\'re near the ocean, be aware of the danger of tsunamis the occurrence of a major earthquake. Climb to higher ground. If you\'re in a public place filled with people, avoid panic and do not rush to the exit. Stay low and cover your head and neck with your hands and arms.
</string>
    <string name="short_comoactuar_info">Upon the occurrence of an earthquake usually people do not know what to do, fear makes the...</string>
    <string name="long_comoactuar_whattodo">First you must remain calm and protect in a safe place in the place where you are. Once the earthquake finished you should go to evacuation routes and remember not to use elevators. Besides being prepared and take precautions in your home, planning the following: "\n" "\n""\n"
-Agreeing a safe place to shelter and a meeting place in case your family group dispersion in the quake. "\n" "\n"
-Check That your housing facilities both electric and gas, are in good condition. "\n" "\n"
To prepare an emergency kit with basic items. "\n" "\n"
Identify risk objects such as pictures, objects can move or break windows, staying away from them during the quake.
</string>
    <string name="short_comoactuar_whattodo">First you must remain calm and protect in a safe place in the place where you are. Once...</string>
    <string name="long_comoactuar_dato">The fire can be caused by power outage damage subsequent to the gas network of large cities. A prominent case of this type of event is the 1906 earthquake in San Francisco, where fires caused more victims than the earthquake itself.</string>
    <string name="short_comoactuar_dato">The fire can be caused by power outage damage subsequent to the gas network of large cities...</string>

    <string name="long_lugar_info">If during an earthquake you are in an inside security zones correspond to the toughest parts of a good construction, which are often the corners, corners, pillars and the area under the door frame. "\n" "\n"
If you are outside, you find a safe place walking away with tambourines, buildings, cornices, ducts, chimneys, trees, poles, power lines or other latent danger.
</string>
    <string name="short_lugar_info">If during an earthquake you are in an inside security zones correspond to the toughest parts of...</string>
    <string name="long_lugar_whattodo">It is very important that you define in advance a meeting with your family group in case of an earthquake, as communications may be cut. This place should be accessible to all and secure. "\n" "\n"
Remember to set a place in every room of the house where they can be placed in case of an earthquake, it should be a position where nothing could fall on them. "\n" "\n"
They can also reduce injury or damage to their belongings securing them in the first place. Secure top heavy to walls with flexible straps furniture part. Use caulk or Velcro fasteners for objects on tables, shelves or other furniture. Install safety latches on cabinets to keep them closed.
</string>
    <string name="short_lugar_whattodo">It is very important that you define in advance a meeting with your family group in case...</string>
    <string name="long_lugar_dato">For people with limited mobility, the movement can increase the difficulty to move or stay balanced. Try to get to the floor in a sitting position and into a wall. Protect your head and neck with your arms and hands. "\n" "\n"
For people with impaired hearing, before an earthquake, identify and test multiple ways to receive warnings and information to evacuate. "\n" "\n"
</string>
    <string name="short_lugar_dato">For people with limited mobility, the movement can increase the difficulty to move or stay...</string>

<string name="long_kit_info">Supermarkets and the most services during an earthquake are closed, so the option to source (food, medicines, water, etc.) will be zero through these means. Besides electricity, water, gas and telephone systems is highly likely not to work after an earthquake. Which generates a rapid shortage of basic resources. Which can generate crisis in the public and robberies shops and innocent people for this.</string>
    <string name="short_kit_info">Supermarkets and the most services during an earthquake are closed, so the option to source (food...</string>
    <string name="long_kit_whattodo">To be prepared for an event of this type, a list of the following basic elements that you must have: "\n" "\n""\n"
- Flashlight batteries"\n" "\n"
- Battery-powered radio. "\n" "\n"
- Spare batteries. "\n" "\n"
- Kit, which has at least disinfectant, cotton, gauze, tape, band aids, aspirin. "\n" "\n"
- Energy Food and / or canned for about 5 days. "\n" "\n"
-Bottled water. "\n" "\n"
- Coats. "\n" "\n"
- Plastic bags to store your garbage. "\n" "\n"
- Toilet paper and / or tissues and toiletries. "\n" "\n"
- Cash (since the ATM will not be in operation).</string>
    <string name="short_kit_whattodo">To be prepared for an event of this type, a list of the following basic elements that you...</string>
    <string name="long_kit_dato">How to create a home extinguisher: Pour 4 tablespoons of baking on a napkin and close as if it were a bag, tying with some sewing thread. Enter a 5 tablespoons of vinegar in a small plastic bottle, put the small bag inside the bottle so that the hang without touching the vinegar, tying a portion of the wire out. Immediately replace the lid. On one side of the bottle, taping a piece of wire attached to a pin capable of piercing the bottle. With everything ready, to shake the bottle and make a hole in the lid, whereby the mixture off the fire trigger.</string>
    <string name="short_kit_dato">How to create a home extinguisher: Pour 4 tablespoons of baking on a napkin and close as if it were...</string>


</resources>
